ABIRAL SUBEDI

Software Engineer · Norfolk, Virginia· +1-757-559-7201 abiral0999@gmail.com· linkedin.com/in/abiral-subedi· github.com/abiralsubedi

Software Engineer with more than four years of experience in full-stack development and leading product cycle from conception to completion. Guided a team of 7 members through 3 product launches at a recent experience in a high-growth eLearning technology startup.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Old Dominion University, Norfolk, Virginia

Aug 2022 – Present

Graduate Research Assistant - Hands-on Lab

- Designed a normalized MySQL database and implemented efficient REST APIs for a survey taking application.
- Created staging and production environment for React and Node.js based applications using AWS EC2 instance, RDS, Nginx, and GoDaddy DNS.
- Integrated payment service from Square and automated delivery service from Nash in a US-based restaurant application; increased sales rate by 28%.
- Worked with team members on existing applications to fix bugs and develop new features; completed tickets ahead of scheduled timelines.

Innovate Tech, Kathmandu, Nepal

Jan 2019 – Jul 2022

Software Engineer - My Second Teacher Application Development Team

- Developed, tested, and integrated React-based applications with performant REST APIs with support for localization, increasing user engagement by 10%
- Collaborated with internal teams, including graphic design and QA testers to launch a real-time chat application in 3 months, ahead of schedule by 1 month
- Designed and developed a competency evaluator system for students to assess their knowledge using automated test papers which improved user satisfaction by 26%
- Built and released standalone dummy UI-Components library and integrated it with multiple projects with maximum code reuse
- Created a Business Intelligence tool for interactive dashboarding and visualizing KPI scorecards, saving 15 hours a week of manual reporting work
- Migrated related micro-services to the monorepo structure using Nx that enhanced 30% efficiency on release management and code reusability
- Analyzed areas of improvement and optimized API requests by using caching and auto revalidation which eliminated 15% of unnecessary requests
- Wrote reusable unit test documents to ensure quality control and detect bugs by increasing over 30% efficiency rate
- Collaborated with QA software testers to conduct E2E testing using Cypress, improving software accuracy by approximately 20%
- Built responsive and interactive user interfaces, increasing mobile traffic by 24%

Rigo Technologies, Kathmandu, Nepal

Sep 2018 – Dec 2018

Software Developer Intern

- Implemented 60+ E2E tests using Selenium & Protractor
- Worked with senior team members to assist the development of 3 applications on a wide variety of platforms including web and mobile

EDUCATION

Old Dominion University, Norfolk, Virginia

Aug 2022 - Apr 2024

Master's of Science in Computer Science

London Metropolitan University, London, UK

Jul 2018 - May 2021

Bachelor's of Science in Computing

SKILLS

Languages: JavaScript, TypeScript, Java, Python

Frameworks/Libraries: React, Node.js, Express.js, Spring Boot, Android Studio, React Native, Next.js,

Redux, Capacitor, Redis, React Testing Library, Storybook, Cypress

Databases: MongoDB, MySQL, PostgreSQL

Cloud Platform: AWS Code Pipeline and CodeBuild, EC2, S3, SES, Lambda, SQS

SDLC: Agile with Scrum (Jira) Version Control: Git, Github, Gitlab

Continuous Integration/Deployment: Docker, Webpack

Platforms: Linux, Windows